<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The beholder within]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The beholder within]]></description>
        <link>http://avatarbrain.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 15:00:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://avatarbrain.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 15:00:29 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Most powerful is he who has himself in his own power ―Seneca]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/d1913a5b-d596-48cf-821a-70b242b21c78.png" title="Most powerful is he who has himself in his own power &horbar;Seneca" alt="&quot;Isolated by the most savage terrain in North America, the reclusive Tarahumara Indians of Mexico&rsquo;s deadly Copper Canyons are custodians of a lost art. For centuries, they have practiced techniques that allow them to run hundreds of miles without rest and chase down anything from a deer to an Olympic marathoner while enjoying every mile of it. Their superhuman talent is matched by uncanny health and serenity, leaving the Tarahumara immune to the diseases and strife that plague modern existence.&quot;  &horbar;Christopher McDougall">]]></description>
            <link>https://xeroshoes.com/wp-content/themes/commercegurus/images/home-features/support-tarahumara.jpg</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">61afded6-18b2-45e9-a4eb-d7d975356938</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 22:41:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Are Our Brain’s Avatar …And Until We Recode It, The Store’s Avatars Я Us!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/69cc6f5aa2e07d256d2fb60d0c3e82d0/croprotate.png?cropheight=4910&cropwidth=7360&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc79d3ac5-6db6-4deb-b211-4021caf4517d.png&x=0&y=0" alt="Everything we see is a perspective, not the truth &horbar;Marcus Aurelius">,<h1>We Are Our Brain’s Avatar …And Until We Recode It, The Store’s Avatars Я Us!</h1>,<p>Visualizing our brain as a web-server and culture as a network, reveals why perceptual experience causes so many interpretations and with each, a different destiny</p>,<p><strong>CEREBRAL (SOFTWARE)</strong></p>,<p>Imagine our brains are web servers powering a +7 billion network, where culture is a web-server language, while human language can only code web content. Question: If a group of coders became aware of this design, would they tell us? Or would they concentrate on coding “cultural illusions” they can sell to the rest of us, so they can become the most powerful elite on earth?</p>,<p><strong>KEYMAKER</strong></p>,<p>CPU stands for Central Processing Unit, yet regarding our brain, it refers to our Limbic System: Completely Primitive Unconscious</p>,<p>OS stands for Operating System in computers. Organized Screener in our case, one of the many executive functions of the Prefrontal Cortex</p>,<p>I/O (Input/Output) monitor, keyboard, mouse, etc. help CPUs interact, as our sensory receptors (eyes, ears, nose, taste buds, skin, etc.) help us</p>,<p>Software Contains the commands for computers to do their work. In our case, these commands are fed since infancy, via sounds, colors, flavors, aromas, etc. to set what stimuli spur enough dopamine to keep us coming for more</p>,<p><strong>PHYSICAL (HARDWARE)</strong></p>,<p>Many of the foods and habits said to prolong our health might be harmful or at best useless over time. For instance, when it comes to:</p>,<p>Nutrition Keeping our brain healthy depends on this factor more than any. Yet, as shown in <a href="http://www.infoasy.com/">Hack The Matrix</a>, it is difficult to change our fate in this area, unless we realize our senses were bred since young, to crave foods bearing no nutritional value and high odds of triggering irreversible cell-damage</p>,<p>Exercise Most of us think of it as a way of counteracting the effects of unhealthy eating habits, a notion fueling our yearning for useless gear. For instance, as posted in <a href="https://www.strava.com/clubs/huarache-runners">Huarache Runners</a> and explained by Chris McDougall (<a href="http://www.infoasy.com/">Appendix B</a>), the larger the gap between our soles’ nerve endings and the surface we run on, the higher the potential for injury</p>,<p><strong>FINANCIAL (POWER)</strong></p>,<p>Linked below are 3 concepts that provide long-range perspective on what truly underlies financial matters</p>,<p><a href="http://sequoian.com/2015/09/wp-contentuploads201610the-discount-rate-pyramid-scheme-2-0-pdf/">Interest Rates</a>: The price of uncertainty</p>,<p><a href="http://sequoian.com/2017/08/wp-contentuploads201708predator-prey2-pdf/">Net Present Value</a>: Uncertainty rules the value of future cash flows</p>,<p><a href="http://sequoian.com/2016/03/wp-contentuploads201708information_symmetry-pdf/">Information Symmetry</a>: Insight*People/Uncertainty= EXP Wealth Growth</p>,<p><strong>SOCIAL (NETWORK)</strong></p>,<p>Social interaction follows rules of engagement established by our animal brain’s perceived social status. Thus, optimizing our “net protocol” rests on identifying, committing to, and incorporating high-rank behavior code, despite unique constraints</p>,<p><strong>TO BE CONTINUED…</strong></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://unsplash.com/@emanuelebresciani?photo=9xAvbCVi-Nk) </link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">961fe17a-0d2a-47ed-be24-1ca0403deb2a</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:53:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hijacked!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Hijacked!</strong></h1>,<h2><strong>Despite her entering the weight-loss industry, NISOD Excellence Award professor, double PhD (Brain &amp; Cognitive Sciences) &amp; Berkeley summa cum laude, Dr. Susan Peirce’s video is irrefutable: Form, rather than “Substance” lurks behind all addictive foods</strong></h2>,<p><strong>CEREBRAL (SOFTWARE): </strong>2 of the substances pictured here are everyday foods, the other 2 are street drugs. All 4 cause dopamine-spike responses from the <a href="https://www.reference.com/science/limbic-system-39014f3c7323b28c?qo=cdpArticles">Limbic System</a> that hijack our <a href="https://www.reference.com/science/prefrontal-cortex-3a271896b743339b">Pre-frontal Cortex</a>’s ability to think. This part of <a href="http://susanpeircethompson.com/about-susan/">Dr. Peirce’s</a> video, starts on minute 35:00, yet <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J5YvefCIqHk">all of it is worth watching</a></p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/1832a27444f6cf2b56ca82ee31253801289c3b32.png">]]></description>
            <link>http://avatarbrain.com/hijacked/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8e3093b5-ff56-406f-9eb9-4b1a93e36dfb</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 02:16:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>